SAMUEL MWAMBURI MGHENDI

DATA ANALYST

SUMMARY

A driven individual committed to learning and collaboration with 2 years of experience in Data Science and Software Development. I have a strong background in Math, Statistics, and Programming and keen on developing clean and functional but complex systems.

CONTACT

Sam.mwamburi@gmail.com

\(+254716245353

♥ Nairobi, Kenya

in linkedin.com/in/mwamburi

nghendi 🕜

EDUCATION

University of Sept. 2020 to Nairobi Current M.Sc. Computational Intelligence 2022

Moi Sept. 2014 to Dec. University 2019 B.Sc. Informatics 2019

EMPLOYMENT

United Nations Environment Programme

Information Management Specialist

Nairobi, Kenya July 2019 to Current

Perform data analysis and business intelligence reporting for UNEP's Executive Office and Law Division. I have also undertaken the development of UNEP's projects performance monitoring and portfolio analysis tool on the Projects Information Management System (projects.unep.org).

Nairobi, Kenya

Information Management and Systems Intern Sept. 2017 to Mar. 2018 Conducted the development and migration of the upgraded UNEP Online Document Repository (wedocs.unep.org) platform.

AMPATH Kenya

Eldoret, Kenya

Information Technology Intern

May 2016 to Aug. 2016

Performed enterprise server and network installation and configuration, enduser software installation and maintenance, and administrative support.

PROJECTS

Projects Information Management System (PIMS+)

Aug. 2019 to Current

Undertaken the design and development of the projects monitoring extension to

UNEP's projects performance monitoring and portfolio analysis tool.

UNEP Online Document Repository (WeDocs) Sept. 2017 to Feb. 2018 Conducted the development and migration of UNEP's upgraded Online Document Repository.

Weather in Image

Mar. 2021 to Apr. 2021

Developed a Bayesian model for the probabilistic detection of weather and air quality using a microcontroller.

SKILLS

Tools & Python, SQL, JavaScript, Linux, CodeIgniter, PowerBI, Azure,

Technologies Exc Industry Dat

Data Visualization, Web Development, Data Warehousing,

Database Management

AWARDS

Meltwater Foundation · MEST Africa Scholarship June 2019 MEST Africa offers a graduate-level entrepreneurial training program, seed fund, and an incubator to 60 of Africa's next leading software entrepreneurs each year.

Google · Google Africa Challenge Scholarship

May 2018

Through a partnership with Andela and Udacity, Google sponsors selected
African students to pursue online Web development courses and nanodegrees.